NETFLIX オリジナルシリーズ
（相模(さがみ)）
あの装備
どこのチームのヤツらだ？
Considering their gear,
they're part of some team.
It's the Special Forces' Black Rabbit.
（篠山(しのやま)）特務の黒ウサギ
（一同）あっ
Those are the guys
that captured Tachibana.
（遙香(はるか)）
前に橘(たちばな)さんをさらった連中よ
（アイコ）あっ！
あ…
I never thought
they would chase us this far.
（相模）
まさか 俺たちを追って
こんなとこまで…
Yuya Kanzaki!
（小佐波(おざなみ)）
神崎雄哉(かんざきゆうや)
This is the Ozanami Squad of the CAAC
Malignant Area Security Forces.
我々はＣＡＡＣ(シーエーエーシー)マリグナントエリア
保安部隊所属 小佐波班だ
橘アイコを即時解放し 投降せよ
Release Aiko Tachibana
and surrender immediately.
従わない場合
実力行使の用意がある
If you do not obey,
we're prepared to use force.
もう一度 言う
I repeat,
release Aiko Tachibana
and surrender immediately.
今すぐ橘アイコを解放し
おとなしく投降しろ
（アイコ）あっ 神崎君
Kanzaki!
There's no response.
（隊員）応答ありません
うっ
あっ
（小佐波）撃て
Fire.
（相模）なに！
What the hell?
-They fired!
-Into the Matter!
（雄哉）マターに…
（白石(しらいし)）実弾？
（アイコ）うっ…
Are you kidding me?
（楓(かえで)）ウソでしょ！
〜
They've activated the Matter!
（楓）
ただでさえ 活性化してたのに！
It worked!
（楓）やった！
No, it didn't.
ダメだ…
-The Matter!
-Damn!
（一樹(かずき)）マターが…
（相模）くそ！
（篠山）水瀬(みなせ)は そっちを押さえろ
（一樹）はい！
-Minase! Cover that flank!
-Yes, sir!
I'm going to help.
俺も出ます
Shiraishi,
白石さん
I'll tell them that I've come willingly.
私が話せば
自分の意思で来てるって
It's pointless.
They're here to take you back.
ムダよ 彼らの目的は奪還なの
They don't care
if you came willingly or not.
あなたの意思は関係ないわ
そんな…
Really?
Prepare to fire.
（小佐波）第二射用意
このまま三六式(さんろくしき)を
橋の たもとまで引き戻す
We'll get the Type 36 to retreat
to the bridge entrance.
（隊員）
バイポット１機 ビートルより離脱
One bipod has separated from the Beetle.
Yuya Kanzaki!
（小佐波）神崎雄哉！
What's happening back there?
（楓）なに？ 後ろ どうしたの？
Kanzaki...
神崎君… あっ
Why are you interfering?
（雄哉）なぜ俺の邪魔をする？
（小佐波）言ったはずだ
I told you before.
We're on orders
to bring back Aiko Tachibana.
我々は 橘アイコ奪還の命を受けて
ここに来ている
We'll ask the questions here.
聞きたいのは こちらのほうだ
What do you think you're doing?
お前は何をしようとしている？
I'm here to end it all.
（雄哉）すべてを終わらせるために
There's something I have to do.
俺には やるべきことがある
Nothing's going to stop me.
だから この先へ行く
What do you mean by "all"?
State your purpose.
すべてとは何だ？
目的を言え
There's no need.
（雄哉）伝える必要はない
Even if I told you,
you people would never understand.
それに 口にしたところで
君たちには理解などできない
Is that so?
そうか
聞こえているわね 橘アイコさん
I know you can hear me, Aiko Tachibana.
Why are you following this man?
あなたは なぜ
この男についていくの？
What do you know about Yuya Kanzaki?
神崎雄哉の何を知っているの？
I...
私は…
His objective is unclear.
He'll only put you in terrible danger.
この男の意味不明な行動がもとで
多くの危険
Lives could be lost as well.
さらには
犠牲を生み出す可能性があるのよ
聞かせてほしい 橘アイコさん
Let me ask you this, Aiko Tachibana.
Why do you trust this man?
あなたはこの男の
何を信じているというの？
（小佐波）ああ！ うわっ！
It's the human form...
（相模）人… 型…
お… 小佐波… さん
Ozanami...
Captain!
隊長！
（隊員）うおっ！
Retreat!
一旦 下がれ！
ぐわっ！
（遙香）光を追ってる？
It's going after the light.
Turn off all your lights!
みんな ライトを！
光を消して！
What about our comms?
（楓）でも通信が…
（篠山）
フォグは薄い
通常無線に切り替える
The fog is thin. Switch to radio!
Cease fire!
（隊員たち）
やめろ！
おい 撃つな！
うわっ！
（遙香）
マターが光に敏感になってる
The Matter is sensitive to light.
（相模）夜だからか？
Because it's night?
ああっ…
We can escape now!
（相模）
今のうちに抜けるぞ
But the tunnel is plugged with Matter!
（楓）
って トンネルは
マターで埋まってんのよ
-Leave that to me!
-What?
（遙香）任せて！
（楓）え？
（遙香）曳光弾(えいこうだん)を使って
We'll use tracer bullets
辺り一帯のマターを引き付ける
to attract the Matter in the area,
then the Beetle's grenade launcher
次にビートルの
グレネードランチャーで
to hit the exit at the far side
of the tunnel with a flare!
山を越えたトンネルの出口に
照明弾を撃って！
The Matter inside the tunnel
will pull out upstream.
トンネルの中にいるマターを
上流側へと引きずり出す
Then, while it's chasing the light...
あとは光を追うマターを…
We'll chase it!
（楓）私らが追う！
（相模）
トンネルを抜けたら 一気に！
We'll run for it once we're through!
There's Matter here!
いる！ マターが
There's some large Matter up ahead.
大きいマターが この先に
ウソでしょ
No way!
We can't attack if it's on the gate.
（篠山）
門番相手に交戦はできん
Spread out
and draw it away from the Beetle!
散開して ビートルから
ヤツの注意をそらす
I'll send out two automated
bipods as decoys.
無人のバイポットも２機
おとりに出す
散れ！
Deploy!
It's all right, Tachibana.
橘 大丈夫だ
This way!
こっちへ
Let's do this!
（篠山）よし
（サイレン）
The upstream side is also active!
（篠山）上流側も活性化してる！
（アイコ）うっ…
I knew it wouldn't work.
やはり効かないか
（２人）あっ…
-Now!
（篠山･白石）せ〜の
Kanzaki, are you okay?
（篠山）
神崎！ 大丈夫か？
We're okay. It stopped moving.
大丈夫です
動きは止まりました
カーボン硬化反応… なぜ？
Carbon hardening? Why?
Tachibana! Are you okay?
橘！ 大丈夫か？
Yes.
（アイコ）う… うん
Tachibana!
（雄哉）橘
It's over.
終わったぞ
The Ozanami Squad?
（南原(なんばら)）小佐波班が？
Yes.
（堀(ほり)）はい
Final communication with them
was at 3:27 a.m. from Moriishi Point.
午前３時27分の森石(もりいし)ポイントを
最後に連絡が途絶えました
（南原）あっ…
If their operations hit a wall,
（黒瀬(くろせ)）
作戦が頓挫(とんざ)したと知れば
南原は すぐに
新しい手を打つはずだ
Nanbara's sure to try
something else soon.
何としても橘アイコを
失いたくないだろうからな
She doesn't want to lose Aiko Tachibana.
（チャイム）
（黒瀬）
こっちは やっておく
I'll handle things here.
（雄哉）
お願いします
Thanks.
We also ran into human form Matter
at the Atobiki Bridge.
それと後曳橋(あとびきばし)で
人型のマターに遭遇しました
Is it the same type
that you faced in Unazuki?
（黒瀬）
前に宇奈月(うなづき)でかち合ったのと
同タイプか？
エビデンスは？
And Evidence?
It's not in there yet.
（雄哉）
まだ得られていません
It could be derived from normal Matter.
通常マターの派生型なのか
But I can't understand
why it would take that shape.
なぜあんな形態を取るのか
理屈が分からない
What? Both teams passed the competition?
（楓）
ええ！ どっちもコンペ合格？
Come on, Shino!
（相模）おい 篠(しの)さん
What was the point
in having the competition?
それじゃ コンペは
何の意味があったんだよ
（一樹）
いいじゃないですか
合格したんですし
Does it matter? We passed.
Anyway, looking forward
to having you around, Aiko.
そんなわけで アイコちゃん
この先もよろしく！
What?
ん？
Yes.
うん
Let me revise what I said before.
（篠山）改めて言わせてくれ
I need all of you for this mission.
この任務には 君たち全員が必要だ
Will you accept it?
引き受けてくれるか？
（一同）おっ
Yes, of course.
ああ もちろんだ
We'll accept it.
引き受けるわ
Jeez! These guys are coming, too?
あ〜あ
この先もこいつらと 一緒か
Stop complaining.
You know you're happy about it.
何だよ
お前が いちばんうれしいくせに
Hey! I am not!
ちょっ… うるさいな！
Wow! You're unusually honest.
（相模）おっ！ 珍しく素直だな
（遙香）フフフッ
-Thanks.
-For what?
（篠山）ありがとうな
（雄哉）え？
（篠山）
この依頼 もらってなかったら
If I hadn't gotten this mission,
I never could have imagined
going this deep
もう一度
エリアから先に向かおうなんて
into the Area again.
考えもできなかった
That's how I feel.
（雄哉）俺の言葉です
We finally made it back here
（白石）
ようやく戻ってこられたわね
特務を辞めて以来
立ち入れなかったこの場所へ
for the first time
since we quit Special Forces.
That's right.
（篠山）ああ
And the real fight is still to come.
そして ここからが本番だ
You're right.
（白石）そうね
（小佐波）ああ！ うわっ！
Stop! Cease fire!
（隊員たち）
やめろ！
おい 撃つな！
うわっ！
（グミ）キュイ？
We'll leave as soon as
the vehicles are charged,
（雄哉）
車両の充電が完了次第
ここを出る
Try to get some sleep.
少しでも仮眠を…
（グミ）キュ キュ…
Is something wrong?
（雄哉）どうかしたか？
Can we reconsider our future plans?
ここから先のこと
考え直せないかな？
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
We can't take everyone
any farther than this.
このまま みんなに連れてもらって
先には行けない
行っちゃいけない
We must not!
I wonder what the hell the objective is.
（一樹）
あいつの目的って何なんすかね？
It has nothing to do with us.
（相模）
俺たちには関係のない話だろ
（一樹）関係あります！
Yes, it does!
I mean, Aiko seemed...
その… アイコちゃんには…
pretty depressed.
元気なかったですし…
She saw people die.
（相模）目の前で人が死んだんだ
そりゃ まいるだろうよ
That's a shocking thing to see.
All the reason more to protect her.
その分 俺たちが
しっかり守ってやればいい
Roger, that.
はい
They can't go.
（アイコ）行けない
Kazuki, Kaede, and the others.
一樹さんも楓さんもみんな
私たちのために
危険な目になんて遭わせられない
I can't put them in danger for our sake.
They knew the danger coming into this.
（雄哉）それは皆 覚悟の上だ
But, after what happened on the bridge...
（アイコ）
だけど 橋の上であんなこと…
If you get to Primary Point,
（雄哉）
君がプライマリー･ポイントへ
行けば
the Burst can be stopped.
バーストは終息される
We'll return your duplicate body
and rescue your family.
偽物の体は元に戻り
君の家族も救え―
We'll solve everything.
すべての問題は解決するんだ
Is it really all right
to put everyone in danger for that?
でも そのために
みんなの命を危険にしていいの？
I don't think so.
きっと違う
That would never make Mom or Ryota happy.
そんなこと
お母さんも亮太(りょうた)も喜ばない
I can't get everyone involved.
I can't take them farther!
私 やっぱり
みんなを巻き添えにして
先へは行けない
（雄哉）ほかの誰も関係ない！
（アイコ）あっ…
Those other people don't matter!
I want to save Aiko Tachibana.
俺は橘アイコを救いたいんだ
あっ…
But why?
どうして そんな…
I can't understand this, Kanzaki.
分からないよ 神崎君
We're all headed for the same place.
（アイコ）
同じ場所を目指していて
それでも みんなに
隠さなくちゃいけないの？
Do we have to keep it
a secret from everyone?
私は ちゃんとみんなに話したい
I want to tell everyone the reason
爆心地へ行く理由も
we're going to Ground Zero,
私の体が 脳以外
and that my body, except for my brain,
全身すべて人工生体だってことも
is made entirely of artificial organisms.
はっ！
I want them to know everything.
（アイコ）
全部 知ってもらいたい
I deleted the data you told me to
from the Kiryu Hospital server.
（小春）
消しといたわよ
桐生(きりゅう)病院のサーバから
頼まれたデータ
Thanks for that.
（黒瀬）助かった
I found something interesting
while I was in there.
（小春）
潜り込む途中で
面白いもの 見つけたんだけど
You did?
（黒瀬）あん？
These are a patient's vitals.
（黒瀬）患者のバイタルか
Zero consciousness level?
What's wrong with this patient?
意識レベル ゼロ？
この患者がどうした？
It's not my field, so I can't really tell,
（小春）
私は専門家じゃないから
よく分かんないんだけど
but when you trace her brainwaves,
they match up with certain events.
この波形 たどってくと
あるイベントの日とリンクしてるわ
For example, July 23.
例えば ７月23日
（黒瀬）マターが大活性した日
The day the Matter became active.
And...
（小春）そして
here's the patient.
これが その患者
Yuzuha!
（黒瀬）柚葉(ゆずは)ちゃん！
You know her?
（小春）知ってる子？
She's the only daughter of Kyosuke Isazu,
an artificial organism developer.
人工生体の共同開発者
伊佐津恭介(いさづきょうすけ)の一人娘
What the hell is going on here?
どういうことだ？ 一体
Are Yuzuha's brain activity
and the Matter's activity linked?
柚葉ちゃんの脳の活動が
マターの活性とリンクしてる？
This is bad.
マズい
This is something
that Yuya never imagined!
これは雄哉が全く予想してない
ファクターだぞ
Dr. Kiryu,
（伊佐津）桐生先生
the Cell Assembler that you developed,
先生が生み出したセル･アセンブラ
そして由良(ゆら)が進化させた
セル･アセンブラ２
and the further development by Yura
of Cell Assembler Two,
have been on ice for a long time.
I'm starting research on them again.
（伊佐津）
長らく凍結していましたが
研究を再開させます
I see.
（桐生）そうか
It's the future of humanity.
（伊佐津）
あれは人類の行く末を担うものです
We need it to deal with the Burst,
and to make progress.
バーストの処理のためにも
前へ進める必要があると
Leave it to me.
私にお任せください
Even without Yura...
（伊佐津）由良なんていなくても
and without the Yura Notes...
由良ノートなんてものがなくても
I swear that I will save you.
お前は お父さんが必ず
I know you can hear me, Yuzuha.
聞こえてるんだろ？ 柚葉
Dad!
（柚葉）お父さん！
お父さ〜ん！
Headed home from school?
（伊佐津）学校帰りか？
Yes.
（柚葉）うん
あっ 由良先生！
Dr. Yura!
Yuzuha.
柚葉ちゃん
Do you remember your promise for today?
ねえ 今日の約束 覚えてる？
What was it?
あ〜 何だっけ？
You said you'd listen to me
play the violin!
もう！ 柚葉のバイオリン
聴いてくれるって言ったでしょ
Oh, that's right.
ああ〜 そう
いっぱい練習したんだからね
I practiced really hard, you know.
Dr. Yura?
由良先生？
Go ahead. Let me hear it.
いいよ 聴かせて
What? Here?
え？ ここで？
（バイオリンの演奏）
（篠山）Ｋ２から先
The area for the rest of this mission,
from K2 until Primary Point,
プライマリー･ポイントまでの
工程は
hasn't been visited since the CAAC
Special Forces pulled out.
対策庁の特務編成部隊が
撤退して以降
誰もダイブインしたことのない
エリアだ
Stay on your guard!
気を引き締めていくぞ
I can see the Number Two
Power Plant at the relay point.
（楓）
見えてきたよん
中継ポイントの第二発電所
There's activity on the rail line!
レール軌道上に活性体反応を確認！
The railway ahead is blocked!
この先の線路がふさがってます
Evidence?
（相模）エビデンスは？
No previous contact. It's a new type!
（一樹）
コンタクト事例なし
新種です！
Have you found out anything?
どう？ 何か分かった？
No. As we get closer to Primary Point,
（雄哉）
いや プライマリー･ポイントに
近づいて
the contact field produced by the Matter
マターが形成する
コンタクトフィールドは
むしろ強くなっているのに
is getting stronger.
信号自体が捉えにくくて
It's hard to even get a signal now.
向こうの意識レベルが
さらに低下しているのかしら
I wonder if her consciousness level there
is decreasing even more.
We have to reach her
before it completely disappears.
完全に消失する前に
何としても たどりつかないと
And then there's her reaction.
（雄哉）それに あの反応…
We may have less time than I thought.
時間は思った以上に
少ないのかもしれない
It's coming!
あっ 来る
What?
え？
（楓）えっ！
The railway's blocked!
Bringing in the Beetle!
（白石）
軌道がふさがれた！
ビートルも下に降りる
The activity is too widespread!
（楓）反応範囲 広すぎ！
Pull back behind the Beetle!
（篠山）ビートルは後方で待機
進路が確保できるまで
ヘビーレーザーで援護を頼む
Cover us with the heavy laser
until we clear the way!
Roger!
（白石）了解！
I'll fire the laser.
俺がレーザー 撃ちます
一樹！ マターのかけらは
たくさん作ったぜ
Kazuki, I made a ton
of Matter fragments!
I found some crystallized Matter!
（一樹）結晶化マター 感知！
Got it!
確保！
Here it comes, Kanzaki!
来た！ 神崎！
I sent you the data!
データ送ったぞ！
白石さん レーザー 頼みます
Take over the laser, Shiraishi.
（白石）分かった
Roger!
あっ また来る！
It's coming again!
Matter?
マター？
真下から？
It's under us?!
Aiko, are you okay?
アイコちゃん 大丈夫？
Yes.
はい
Aiko?
（白石）アイコちゃん？
What are you...
あなた…
I'll take the laser.
（アイコ）私が撃ちます
Tachibana!
（雄哉）橘！
先へ進むなら 私も戦う
If we're doing this,
then I'm fighting, too!
I don't want anyone to die!
誰も… 誰にも死んでほしくない！
（アイコ）くっ…
（白石）アイコちゃん
Aiko!
Finished!
（雄哉）出来た
カートリッジ送りました！
I sent the cartridges!
Here goes another!
もう１便 出します
Again!
あっ また！
ううっ！
-It's Matter!
-Kanzaki!
（白石）マター！
（アイコ）神崎君！
Aiko, get down!
アイコちゃん 伏せて！
あっ！
（アイコ）きゃあ〜！
（アイコ）神崎君！
（雄哉）橘！
-Kanzaki!
-Tachibana!
（アイコ）きゃあ！
あ…
はっ！
What is this?
（アイコ）何？
（アイコ）あっ…！
あっ
グミ？ あっ…
Gummi?
～
うっ
あっ…
Aiko!
&lrm;（白石）アイコちゃん！
-Tachibana!
-Aiko!
（雄哉）橘！
（白石）アイコちゃん！
Kanzaki, I'll get her out with the Beetle!
（白石）
神崎君 ビートルで何とかする！
What happened?
どうした？
Aiko is buried under crystallized Matter.
（白石）
アイコちゃんが
結晶化マターの下敷きに…
なに！
-What?
えっ！
-No way!
-I'll use the Beetle to get her out.
えっ？
アイコちゃんは
ビートルで対処します
Everyone, your job is to tranquilize
the Matter with the synthesized chemicals!
皆さんは シンセ済みの薬剤による
マターの鎮静化を
優先してください！
This can't be happening!
ウソだろ！
Tachibana!
橘！
Active Matter cleared.
Beetle's path secured.
（遙香）
活性化マター オールクリア
ビートルの進路を確保しました
（一樹）アイコちゃん！
Aiko!
Is she all right?
（相模）嬢ちゃんは無事か？
They're both outside without suits?
（遙香）
２人ともスーツなしで外へ？
（一同）おぉ
Hey! What the hell is going on?
（一樹）
おい 何だよ これ
どういうことだよ
Those are carbon nanostructures.
（相模）
カーボン･ナノ･ストラクチャ…
But, I thought that only happened
to artificial organisms.
（楓）
だって あれは
人工生体のオプション
I'll clean her in the bipod.
バイポットで洗浄します
Clean her? But she's not wearing a suit.
（楓）
洗浄ってそんな… スーツなしで？
It's all right.
（遙香）大丈夫
（一同）えっ？
She's not a normal human.
彼女 普通の人間じゃないから
（楓･一樹）え？
-What?
She's a composite.
（遙香）彼女 合成体なのよ
A composite of a real brain
and an artificial organism body.
生身の脳と
全身人工生体との合成体
（３人）あっ…
Aiko is a composite?
アイコちゃんが合成体？
Is that even possible?
そんなの ありえるわけ？
あっ…
うっ
Hey, if that's true,
it means the whole time
（相模）
おい それが事実だとすりゃ
we've been in the Area,
俺たちは
エリアに入ってからここまで
we've been dragging Matter bait with us.
マターのエサを連れて
歩かされてきたってことか
〜
Subtitle translation by Brian Athey